

aaditi@newschool.edu
 adi.aditi.net@gmail.com
 (646) 851 3989

WORK EXPERIENCE

HONEYWELL AEROSPACE

LEAD DESIGNER. DATA VISUALIZATION (Feb 2017 - Jun 2018)

Worked on Data Visualization, UX UI design of an **Advanced Technology** project - demonstrating the ability to work efficiently under high risk, critical applications.

Iconography: Created a family of new icons dedicated to the flight events and successfully filed a patent for these icons during my tenure at Honeywell Aerospace.

Led a team of 3 on a fast-paced (green-house) project as Data Visualization Designer, Design researcher, UX UI Designer for the software component of **GNSS navigation device HGuide** - UAV, UGV demonstrating leadership under workload pressure.

BARCLAYS TECHNOLOGY CENTRE INDIA

UX UI DESIGNER (Apr 2015 - Feb 2017)

UX UI for **mobile banking applications** requiring user research and understanding of users from different age groups, alternate and advanced banking methods, web interface design for Barclays UK online banking website in agile methodology.

Worked in small teams on end-to-end design process - Design research & Analysis, Product promo, Iconography, Information design, User Centric Design, UX UI revamp of android, iOS and windows based mobile application.

HONEYWELL AEROSPACE

DESIGN INTERN (Aug 2014 - Mar 2015)

My project here involved analysis and comparative analysis of the **flight deck displays** across Honeywell's Aerospace domain, Visual design revamp concepts of futuristic flight deck displays, UX, UI for **Honeywell's Pilatus 12NG** flight deck (as a pilot design), Visual Design revamp of Synoptic Diagrams- used by pilots for situational status awareness of the aircraft.

EDUCATION

DATA VISUALIZATION (MS)

PARSONS SCHOOL OF DESIGN, NEW YORK. (2018 - 2019)

GRAPHIC DESIGN (MDes)

NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF DESIGN, INDIA (2012 - 2015)

E&TC ENGINEERING (BE)

PUNE INSTITUTE OF COMPUTER TECHNOLOGY, INDIA.

(2006 - 2010)

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Data Visualization, Data Analytics, User Experience Design (UX), User Interface Design (UI), Graphics, Infographics, Design Research, Design Thinking, Information Architecture, Layout Design, Branding & Identity, Design Prototyping, Iconography, Photography, Minimal Art & Illustration, Motion Capture

TOOLKIT

Adobe Creative Suite, Sketch pro, Axure pro, InVision, Processing, Google Suite, Tableau, Jira, Primary knowledge of AWS postgreSQL, DynamoDB, AR VR Tech, Machine Learning, Statistics, GitHub, Computing Languages- Java Script- d3js, p5js, VueJs, Python, R studio, HTML, CSS, Basic SQL

INSPIRED BY SIMPLICITY.
PASSIONATE ABOUT DESIGN.

IBM INDIA PVT. LTD.

APPLICATION DEVELOPER (Jun 2010 - Jun 2012)

Worked on ITES PL (Presentation Layer) of IBM's training search application UI development in Java, environment support and sub applications associated with PL. I do not intend to work as a developer although the technical experience gathered during this work helps with a better understanding of the tech-based design projects and with communicating better with technology teams.

THE NEW SCHOOL

SR, STUDENT ASSISTANT SPECIALIST (Dec 2018 - current)

CA/ University Library/ Digital Library and Technical Services, The New School . This on-campus work opportunity allows me to practice **User Experience Analysis & Design, Data Visualization and UI Design** revamp for the libraries department of The New School.

SUMMARY

With a graduation in technical education, during my MDes post grad education in graphic design, I worked on multiple small projects based on Information Design, UX Research, Visual Design and User Interface design followed by UX Design experience in banking industry for 2 years on end-to-end design for mobile applications. During my tenure in aerospace domain, I led critical, fast-paced and high-risk project. The background in technology helps with a better understanding of the issues on tech-based design projects. Further specialization in Data Visualization contributes towards expanding the horizon my design and technical knowledge enabling me to conduct data analytics alongwith the application of apply UX UI design expertise to weave data into beautiful stories.

I communicate well with teams across the domains- marketing, technology, production etc. conducting user research (interviews, surveys, peer study, user journeys based on user persona, heuristic analysis etc.), working in agile and waterfall methodologies on multiple digital platforms.

During my overall experience of over 5 years, I have operated as a versatile designer taking on responsibilities as a leader, researcher, analyzer, data visualization designer, visual designer and UX UI designer. I am looking for full-time work opportunities in Data Visualization, User Experience (UX), User Interface (UI) Design and Visual Design.